<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata><idinfo><citation><citeinfo><origin>New Jersey Department of Environmental Protection (NJDEP), Office of Information Resources Management (OIRM), Bureau of Geographic Information Systems (BGIS)</origin><pubdate>20101101</pubdate><title>National Hydrography Dataset (NHD) Waterbody 2002 for New Jersey (NHDWaterbody_2002)</title><geoform>vector digital data</geoform><pubinfo><pubplace>Trenton, NJ</pubplace><publish>NJ Department of Environmental Protection (NJDEP)</publish></pubinfo><onlink>http://www.nj.gov/dep/gis/listall.html</onlink><onlink>http://www.nj.gov/dep/gis/geowebsplash.htm</onlink></citeinfo></citation><descript><abstract>NOTE:

This metadata file contains information for Waterbody features delineated for NJ from 2002 color infrared (CIR) imagery with attributes extracted from the National Hydrography Dataset (NHD) .

Digitizing of this data was initally done by Aerial Information Systems, Inc., Redlands, CA, under direction of the New Jersey Department of Environmental Protection (NJDEP), Bureau of Geographic Information System (BGIS).

Conflation of USGS 1:24,000 High resolution NHD attributes was done by Data Enhancement Services, LLC  (DES) partenered with Civil Solutions.  This statewide conflation of NHD High resolution information was completed in 2010.
All QA/QC was done by NJDEP, Bureau of GIS and USGS.
This represents a subset of the statewide extract for NJ dated August 25, 2010.</abstract><purpose>The data set will provide Waterbody  information for regulators, planners, and others interested in hydrography data.

The use of the NHD data layers in hydrologic analyses will provide a means of monitoring "the health of the citizens and ecosystems of New Jersey" through the use of diverse applications.

This data set is intended to serve as a resource for analysis rather than regulatory delineations. The NJDEP may change the line work based on more in depth analysis and field inspection for regulatory purposes.

NJDEP/BGIS is a stewardship partner with USGS in the development of Local resolution data which is NHD compliant.</purpose><supplinf>Users of this data are strongly urged to become familiar with the USGS National Hydrography Dataset (NHD) review documents, as well as others included below, before using the data set.

http://nhd.usgs.gov/index.html</supplinf></descript><timeperd><current>ground condition</current><timeinfo><sngdate><caldate>2002</caldate></sngdate></timeinfo></timeperd><status><progress>In work</progress><update>Irregular</update></status><spdom><bounding><westbc>
-75.649692</westbc><eastbc>
-73.793383</eastbc><northbc>
41.377534</northbc><southbc>
38.778716</southbc></bounding></spdom><keywords><theme><themekt>None</themekt><themekey>Stream</themekey><themekey>Flowline</themekey><themekey>River</themekey><themekey>Water body</themekey><themekey>water quality</themekey><themekey>watersheds</themekey><themekey>watershed management areas</themekey><themekey>NHD</themekey><themekey>NJDEP</themekey><themekey>Hydrography</themekey><themekey>Stream / River</themekey><themekey>Lake / Pond</themekey><themekey>Canal / Ditch</themekey><themekey>Reservoir</themekey><themekey>Spring / Seep</themekey><themekey>Swamp / Marsh</themekey><themekey>Artificial Path</themekey><themekey>Reach Code</themekey><themekey>WBD</themekey><themekey>Watershed Boundary Dataset</themekey></theme><theme><themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt><themekey>inlandWaters</themekey></theme><theme><themekt>U.S. Department of the Interior, U.S. Geological Survey, 1999, Standards for National Hydrography Dataset (http://www.usgs.gov/pubprod/reference.html#standards)</themekt><themekey>NHD</themekey></theme><place><placekt>None</placekt><placekey>New Jersey</placekey><placekey>NJ</placekey><placekey>WMA</placekey></place><place><placekt>U.S. Department of Commerce, 1977, Countries, dependencies, areas of special sovereignty, and their principal administrative divisions (Federal Information Processing Standards 10-3): Washington, D.C., National Institute of Standards and Technology.</placekt><placekey>US</placekey></place><temporal><tempkt>None</tempkt><tempkey>2002</tempkey></temporal><theme><themekt>User</themekt><themekey>NHDWaterbody_2002</themekey><themekey>NHDWaterbody_2002</themekey></theme></keywords><accconst>In most cases, a downloadable version of this layer is also available. Information to download the data can be found in the Distribution Section of this metadata record. This data layer is shown in the NJDEP's NJ-GeoWeb mapping application accessible through the Online Linkage: http://www.nj.gov/dep/gis/geowebsplash.htm</accconst><useconst>New Jersey Department of Environmental Protection (NJDEP)

Data Distribution Agreement

I. Description of Data to be Provided.

The data provided herein are distributed subject to the following conditions and restrictions:

SUBJECT DATA LAYERS

For all data contained herein, NJDEP makes no representations of any kind, including, but not limited to, the warranties of merchantability or fitness for a particular use, nor are any such warranties to be implied with respect to the digital data layers furnished hereunder.  NJDEP assumes no responsibility to maintain them in any manner or form.

II.Terms of Agreement

1. Digital data received from the NJDEP are to be used solely for internal purposes in the conduct of daily affairs.

2. The data are provided, as is, without warranty of any kind and the user is responsible for understanding the accuracy limitations of all digital data layers provided herein, as documented in the accompanying cross-reference files (see SUPPLEMENTAL INFORMATION).  Any reproduction or manipulation of the above data must ensure that the coordinate reference system remains intact.

3. Digital data received from the NJDEP may not be reproduced or redistributed for use by anyone without first obtaining written permission from the NJDEP.  This clause is not intended to restrict distribution of printed mapped information produced from the digital data.

4. Any maps, publications, reports, or other documents produced as a result of this project that utilize NJDEP digital data will credit the NJDEP's Geographic Information System (GIS) as the source of the data with the following credit/disclaimer:

"This (map/publication/report) was developed using New Jersey Department of Environmental Protection Geographic Information System digital data, but this secondary product has not been verified by NJDEP and is not state-authorized."

5.    Users shall require any independent contractor, hired to undertake work that will utilize digital data obtained from the NJDEP, to agree not to use, reproduce, or redistribute NJDEP GIS data for any purpose other than the specified contractual work.  All copies of NJDEP GIS data utilized by an independent contractor will be required to be returned to the original user at the close of such contractual work.

Users hereby agree to abide by the use and reproduction conditions specified above and agree to hold any independent contractor to the same terms.  By using data provided herein, the user acknowledges that terms and conditions have been read and that the user is bound by these criteria.</useconst><browse><browsen>http://www.state.nj.us/dep/gis/digidownload/images/statewide/nhdwaterbody2002.gif</browsen><browsed>image</browsed><browset>GIF</browset></browse><datacred>Craig Coutros and Seth Hackman
NJ Department of Environmental Protection (NJDEP), Office of Information Resources Management (OIRM), Bureau of Geographic Information System (BGIS)
John Bocchino: NJDEP, Metadata Compilier</datacred><native>Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 3; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.2.6.1500</native><crossref><citeinfo><origin>United States Geological Survey (USGS)</origin><pubdate>Unknown</pubdate><title>USGS National Hydrography Dataset Documentation Website</title><geoform>website</geoform><pubinfo><pubplace>Reston, Va</pubplace><publish>USGS</publish></pubinfo><onlink>http://nhd.usgs.gov/documentation.html</onlink></citeinfo></crossref></idinfo><dataqual><attracc><attraccr>NJDEP checked for delineation accuracy, connectivity, digitized "flow" direction, invalid attribute codes and corrected as identified.  Empty fields will be populated in future updates.

Feature types, characteristics, and other attributes conform to the Standards for National Hydrography Dataset (USGS, 1999) as of the date they were loaded into the database.  All names were validated against a current extract from the Geographic Names Information System (GNIS).  The entry and identifier for the names match those in the GNIS.

GNIS_Name is official only if identified by a GNIS_ID.   Any Flowline without a GNIS_ID but displays a GNIS_Name or "tributary" identifier is not official and is for NJDEP referencing purposes only.  These are subject to change when submissions are made to the Board of Geographic Names.</attraccr></attracc><logic>Lines conform to topological rules. Lines intersect only at nodes, and all nodes anchor the ends of lines.  Lines do not overshoot or undershoot other lines where they are supposed to meet.  There are no duplicate lines.  Lines bound areas and lines identify the areas to the left and right of the lines.</logic><complete>Data is available statewide for New Jersey.

This data represents a subset of the August 28, 2010  statewide extract of NHD High Resolution dataset after NJ completed a conflation of NHD attributes to local resolution features.

In general, all polygonal water features were reselected from NHDWaterbody and NHDArea feature classes and combined to create this data layer.

This data is considered Local resolution (1:2400) or better and conforms to all USGS NHD rules. ReachCodes have been defined on all features. Names were applied from the GNIS database during the final upload into the NHD.</complete><posacc><horizpa><horizpar>These maps were compiled to meet National Map Accuracy Standards at 1:2400</horizpar></horizpa><vertacc><vertaccr>NA</vertaccr></vertacc></posacc><lineage><srcinfo><srccite><citeinfo><origin>Keystone Aerial Surveys</origin><pubdate>20020411</pubdate><pubtime>Unknown</pubtime><title>Aerial Imagery Acquisition of the State of New Jersey</title><geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform><pubinfo><pubplace>Philadelphia, PA</pubplace><publish>Keystone Aerial Surveys</publish></pubinfo></citeinfo></srccite><srcscale>2400</srcscale><typesrc>CD-ROM</typesrc><srctime><timeinfo><rngdates><begdate>20020218</begdate><enddate>20020411</enddate></rngdates></timeinfo><srccurr>ground condition</srccurr></srctime><srccitea>Aerial Photography</srccitea><srccontr>Digital color infrared (CIR) orthophotography of New Jersey in State Plane NAD83 Coordinates, U.S. Survey Feet. The digital orthophotography was produced at a scale of 1:2400 (1"=200') with a 1 foot pixel resolution.  Stream data for 2002 was digitized directly from 2002 digital image files.</srccontr></srcinfo><srcinfo><srccite><citeinfo><origin>United States Geological Survey (USGS); NJDEP</origin><pubdate>1995/97</pubdate><title>1995/97 CIR Digital Ortho Quarterquads</title><geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform><pubinfo><pubplace>Reston, Va</pubplace><publish>USGS</publish></pubinfo><othercit>Digital images were created from 1:40000 scale NAPP CIR images by USGS, referenced in UTM, NAD83.  These images were then projected to New Jersey State Plane Feet Coordinates (NJSPF), NAD83, and compressed to JPEG images files.  These NJSPF compressed files were used in the development of the this data set. The original images in UTM are available from the USGS website.  The NJSPF versions are available from the NJDEP site.  Both sites have online and CD distribution of these images.</othercit><onlink>http://edc.usgs.gov</onlink></citeinfo></srccite><srcscale>12000</srcscale><typesrc>online; CDROM</typesrc><srctime><timeinfo><rngdates><begdate>1995</begdate><enddate>1997</enddate></rngdates></timeinfo><srccurr>ground condition</srccurr></srctime><srccitea>USGS; NJDEP</srccitea><srccontr>Land use/land cover for 1995/97 was digitized directly from 1995/97 digital image files.  Photographic transparencies of the CIR images used to create the digital files were also viewed stereoscopically to aid in land use/land cover determinations.</srccontr></srcinfo><procstep><procdate>2010</procdate><procdesc>Photo interpretation of 2002 CIR digital imagery, interactive editing and initial QA/QC was done by Aerial Information Systems, Redlands, CA.  Final QA/QC and final data formatting was done by NJDEP/BGIS.  All Data sets were processed and delivered by Hydrologic Unit 8 (HU8 - Subbasin) and this coding was maintained in the final versions.  The first version was released as Streams_2002.

This update to Streams_2002 data now includes NHD compliant attributes and coding.  NJDEP/BGIS completed a statewide conflation in 2010 to meet the USGS National Hydrography Dataset standards.  The conflation of 1:24,000 NHD high resolution feature attributes to this data was done by Data Enhancement Services, LLC under the direction of Civil Solutions beginning in 2009.   Initial QA/QC was done by NJDEP/BGIS followed by a review by USGS prior to upload into the National database.

QA/QC involved verifying that Flow Direction of each flowline is correct to facilitate the development of geometric networks.  Name Attributes are consistant with the USGS Geographic Names (GNIS) were transferred to this layer appropriately.  All unnamed tributaries flowing into a named water course stream have "tributary" extension in the GNIS_Name field.  GNIS_ID, GNIS_NAME, FTYPE, and FCODE attributes are NHD compliant and were transferred from the NHDgeo data layers.

Only features having a GNIS_ID are official. All other features represent local names subject to review.

This product is an interim product subject to attribute correction.</procdesc></procstep></lineage><cloud>0</cloud></dataqual><spdoinfo><direct>Vector</direct><ptvctinf><esriterm Name="del_trib_waters"><efeatyp Sync="TRUE">Simple</efeatyp><efeageom code="4" Sync="TRUE"></efeageom><esritopo Sync="TRUE">FALSE</esritopo><efeacnt Sync="TRUE">0</efeacnt><spindex Sync="TRUE">FALSE</spindex><linrefer Sync="TRUE">TRUE</linrefer></esriterm></ptvctinf></spdoinfo><spref><horizsys><planar><planci><plance>coordinate pair</plance><coordrep><absres>0.000328</absres><ordres>0.000328</ordres></coordrep><plandu>survey feet</plandu></planci></planar><geodetic><horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn><ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips><semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis><denflat>298.257222</denflat></geodetic></horizsys><vertdef><altsys><altdatum>North American Vertical Datum of 1988</altdatum><altres>0.000100</altres><altunits>feet</altunits><altenc>Explicit elevation coordinate included with horizontal coordinates</altenc></altsys></vertdef></spref><eainfo><detailed Name="del_trib_waters"><enttyp><enttypl>NHDWaterbody_2002</enttypl><enttypd>NHDArea and NHDWaterbody</enttypd><enttypds>USGS</enttypds><enttypt Sync="TRUE">Feature Class</enttypt><enttypc Sync="TRUE">0</enttypc></enttyp><attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">FID</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">FID</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">OID</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">4</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale><attrdef Sync="TRUE">Internal feature number.</attrdef><attrdefs Sync="TRUE">Esri</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom Sync="TRUE">Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl><attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef><attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">OBJECTID</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Integer</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">10</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">10</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>COMID</attrlabl><attrdef>10-digit integer that uniquely identifies the occurrence of each feature.</attrdef><attrdefs>USGS</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Unique identifier assigned by GNIS.</udom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">COMID</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Integer</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">10</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">10</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>FDATE</attrlabl><attrdef>Date of last feature modification.</attrdef><attrdefs>USGS</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Date of last update into the NHD</udom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">FDATE</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Date</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">8</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">PERMANENT_</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">PERMANENT_</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">40</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>RESOLUTION</attrlabl><attrdef>Source resolution. Currently NHD is available as separate resolutions.</attrdef><attrdefs>USGS</attrdefs><attrdomv><edom><edomv>Local</edomv><edomvd>greater than 1:12,000</edomvd></edom></attrdomv><attrdomv><edom><edomv>High</edomv><edomvd>1:24,000/12,000</edomvd></edom></attrdomv><attrdomv><edom><edomv>Medium</edomv><edomvd>1:100,000</edomvd></edom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">RESOLUTION</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Integer</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">10</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">10</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>GNIS_ID</attrlabl><attrdef>Unique identifier assigned by GNIS.</attrdef><attrdefs>USGS</attrdefs><attrdomv><codesetd><codesetn>GNIS</codesetn><codesets>USGS</codesets></codesetd></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">GNIS_ID</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">10</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>GNIS_NAME</attrlabl><attrdef>Proper name, specific term, or expression by which a particular geographic entity is known.</attrdef><attrdefs>USGS</attrdefs><attrdomv><codesetd><codesetn>GNIS</codesetn><codesets>USGS</codesets></codesetd></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">GNIS_NAME</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">65</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>AREASQKM</attrlabl><attrdef>Area of feature in Square Kilometers</attrdef><attrdefs>USGS</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Area of fetaure in Square Kilometers</udom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">AREASQKM</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Double</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>ELEVATION</attrlabl><attrdef>The vertical distance from a given datum.</attrdef><attrdefs>USGS</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Elevation in meters assigned by USGS</udom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">ELEVATION</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Double</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>REACHCODE</attrlabl><attrdef>Unique identifier composed of two parts. The first eight digits is the subbasin code as defined by FIPS 103. The next six digits are randomly assigned, sequential numbers that are unique within a subbasin, 8 digit subbasin followed by unique id.</attrdef><attrdefs>USGS</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Unique identifier assigned by GNIS.</udom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">REACHCODE</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">14</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>FTYPE</attrlabl><attrdef>Three-digit integer value; unique identifier of a feature type.</attrdef><attrdefs>USGS</attrdefs><attrdomv><codesetd><codesetn>Feature Catalog</codesetn><codesets>USGS</codesets></codesetd></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">FTYPE</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Integer</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">10</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">10</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>FCODE</attrlabl><attrdef>Five-digit integer value; composed of the feature type and combinations of characteristics and values.</attrdef><attrdefs>USGS</attrdefs><attrdomv><codesetd><codesetn>Feature Catalog</codesetn><codesets>USGS</codesets></codesetd></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">FCODE</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Integer</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">10</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">10</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>SHAPE</attrlabl><attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef><attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">Shape</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Geometry</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">0</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">FTYPE_DESC</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">FTYPE_DESC</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">50</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">FCODE_DESC</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">FCODE_DESC</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">254</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">SHAPE_Leng</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">SHAPE_Leng</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Double</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">SHAPE_Area</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">SHAPE_Area</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Double</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale><attrdef Sync="TRUE">Area of feature in internal units squared.</attrdef><attrdefs Sync="TRUE">Esri</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom Sync="TRUE">Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">OBJECTID_1</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">OBJECTID_1</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Integer</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">10</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">10</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">Shape_Le_1</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">Shape_Le_1</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Double</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr></detailed><overview><eadetcit>http://nhd.usgs.gov/documentation.html</eadetcit></overview></eainfo><metainfo><metd>20101229</metd><metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn><metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv><mettc>local time</mettc><metextns><onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink><metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof></metextns><metc><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>NJDEP/OIRM/BGIS</cntorg><cntper>Craig Coutros</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>GIS Specialist</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype><address>401 East State Street, Box 428</address><city>Trenton</city><state>New Jersey</state><postal>08625</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>609-777-0672</cntvoice><cntfax>609-292-7900</cntfax><cntemail>gisnet@dep.state.nj.us</cntemail></cntinfo></metc></metainfo><distinfo><distliab>This organization provides the geographic data "as is".  This organization makes no guarantee or warranty concerning the accuracy of information contained in the geographic data.  Also, this organization makes no warranty either expressed or implied, regarding the condition of the product or its fitness for any particular purpose.  The burden for determining fitness for use lies entirely with the user.  Although these files have been processed successfully on computers at this organization, no warranty is made by this organization regarding the use of these data on any other system, nor does the fact of distribution constitute or imply any such warranty.  See also "Use Constraints" for additional distribution and/or data use requirements.</distliab><stdorder><digform><digtinfo><formname>DEP distributes ESRI .SHP and/or GDB. Some data may be NJ GeoWeb "display only" layers.</formname><formvern>latest version</formvern><filedec>WinZip</filedec></digtinfo><digtopt><onlinopt><computer><networka><networkr>http://www.nj.gov/dep/gis/listall.html</networkr><networkr>http://www.nj.gov/dep/gis/geowebsplash.htm</networkr></networka></computer></onlinopt><offoptn><offmedia>None</offmedia><recfmt>None</recfmt></offoptn></digtopt></digform><fees>None</fees><ordering>All available NJDEP public GIS data can be downloaded for free.  Some data shown in NJGeoWeb application may not yet be available for download due to various data or distribution issues.  Please email gisnet@dep.state.nj.us with any data distribution questions.</ordering></stdorder><custom>The NJDEP may distribute GIS data in a variety of formats, such as the ESRI shapefile and/or various versions of the file geodatabase format.  The data also may be available for viewing on various profiles of the NJ GeoWeb online mapping application.  

Note: Some older NJDEP data may not contain .prj files due to distribution procedures at that time. If download does not contain a .prj, please download from:

http://www.nj.gov/dep/gis/njsp83.zip 

Please rename .prj to the name of the downloadable filename. (for example: If Head of Tides filename is HOT.shp, please rename .prj to HOT.prj).  This allows ESRI software to recognize the projection information.</custom><resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc><distrib><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>NJDEP/OIRM/Bureau of GIS</cntorg><cntper>GIS Help Desk</cntper></cntorgp><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype><address>401 East State Street</address><city>Trenton</city><state>NJ</state><postal>08625</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>(609) 777-0672</cntvoice><cntfax>(609) 292-7900</cntfax><cntemail>gisnet@dep.state.nj.us</cntemail></cntinfo></distrib></distinfo><Esri><ModDate>20190625</ModDate><ModTime>12553500</ModTime><CreaDate>20180724</CreaDate><CreaTime>09571600</CreaTime><ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat><SyncOnce>FALSE</SyncOnce><DataProperties><itemProps><itemName Sync="TRUE">del_trib_waters</itemName><imsContentType Sync="TRUE">002</imsContentType><itemSize Sync="TRUE">0.000</itemSize><itemLocation><linkage Sync="TRUE">file://\\dep-tcshared\shared\lum\WM&amp;S\BEAR (Bureau of Environmental Analysis and Restoration)\Envpln\Hourly Employees\KevinZolea\4tribinfo\Del_Tribs_Project\del_tribs_app\shapefiles\del_trib_waters.shp</linkage><protocol Sync="TRUE">Local Area Network</protocol></itemLocation></itemProps><coordRef><type Sync="TRUE">Projected</type><geogcsn Sync="TRUE">GCS_North_American_1983</geogcsn><csUnits Sync="TRUE">Linear Unit: Foot_US (0.304801)</csUnits><projcsn Sync="TRUE">NAD_1983_StatePlane_New_Jersey_FIPS_2900_Feet</projcsn><peXml Sync="TRUE">&lt;ProjectedCoordinateSystem xsi:type='typens:ProjectedCoordinateSystem' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' xmlns:xs='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema' xmlns:typens='http://www.esri.com/schemas/ArcGIS/10.5'&gt;&lt;WKT&gt;PROJCS[&amp;quot;NAD_1983_StatePlane_New_Jersey_FIPS_2900_Feet&amp;quot;,GEOGCS[&amp;quot;GCS_North_American_1983&amp;quot;,DATUM[&amp;quot;D_North_American_1983&amp;quot;,SPHEROID[&amp;quot;GRS_1980&amp;quot;,6378137.0,298.257222101]],PRIMEM[&amp;quot;Greenwich&amp;quot;,0.0],UNIT[&amp;quot;Degree&amp;quot;,0.0174532925199433]],PROJECTION[&amp;quot;Transverse_Mercator&amp;quot;],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;False_Easting&amp;quot;,492125.0],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;False_Northing&amp;quot;,0.0],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;Central_Meridian&amp;quot;,-74.5],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;Scale_Factor&amp;quot;,0.9999],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;Latitude_Of_Origin&amp;quot;,38.83333333333334],UNIT[&amp;quot;Foot_US&amp;quot;,0.3048006096012192],AUTHORITY[&amp;quot;EPSG&amp;quot;,3424]]&lt;/WKT&gt;&lt;XOrigin&gt;-17954600&lt;/XOrigin&gt;&lt;YOrigin&gt;-46918100&lt;/YOrigin&gt;&lt;XYScale&gt;137255069.87923574&lt;/XYScale&gt;&lt;ZOrigin&gt;-100000&lt;/ZOrigin&gt;&lt;ZScale&gt;10000&lt;/ZScale&gt;&lt;MOrigin&gt;-100000&lt;/MOrigin&gt;&lt;MScale&gt;10000&lt;/MScale&gt;&lt;XYTolerance&gt;0.0032808333333333331&lt;/XYTolerance&gt;&lt;ZTolerance&gt;0.001&lt;/ZTolerance&gt;&lt;MTolerance&gt;0.001&lt;/MTolerance&gt;&lt;HighPrecision&gt;true&lt;/HighPrecision&gt;&lt;WKID&gt;102711&lt;/WKID&gt;&lt;LatestWKID&gt;3424&lt;/LatestWKID&gt;&lt;/ProjectedCoordinateSystem&gt;</peXml></coordRef><lineage><Process ToolSource="c:\program files (x86)\arcgis\desktop10.5\ArcToolbox\Toolboxes\Analysis Tools.tbx\Clip" Date="20180807" Time="125812">Clip 4TribstoDEL_R BlacksCrosswicksHUCsfinal "V:\lum\WM&amp;S\BEAR (Bureau of Environmental Analysis and Restoration)\Envpln\Hourly Employees\KevinZolea\4tribinfo\BlacksCrosswicks_waterway.shp" #</Process><Process ToolSource="c:\program files (x86)\arcgis\desktop10.5\ArcToolbox\Toolboxes\Data Management Tools.tbx\Merge" Date="20190625" Time="125545">Merge BlacksCrosswicks_waterway;penn_trib_water;raccoon_waterways;rancocas_waterways "V:\lum\WM&amp;S\BEAR (Bureau of Environmental Analysis and Restoration)\Envpln\Hourly Employees\KevinZolea\4tribinfo\Del_Tribs_Project\del_tribs_app\shapefiles\del_trib_waters.shp" "OBJECTID "OBJECTID" true true false 10 Long 0 10 ,First,#,BlacksCrosswicks_waterway,OBJECTID,-1,-1,penn_trib_water,OBJECTID,-1,-1,raccoon_waterways,OBJECTID,-1,-1,rancocas_waterways,OBJECTID,-1,-1;COMID "COMID" true true false 10 Long 0 10 ,First,#,BlacksCrosswicks_waterway,COMID,-1,-1,penn_trib_water,COMID,-1,-1,raccoon_waterways,COMID,-1,-1,rancocas_waterways,COMID,-1,-1;PERMANENT_ "PERMANENT_" true true false 40 Text 0 0 ,First,#,BlacksCrosswicks_waterway,PERMANENT_,-1,-1,penn_trib_water,PERMANENT_,-1,-1,raccoon_waterways,PERMANENT_,-1,-1,rancocas_waterways,PERMANENT_,-1,-1;FDATE "FDATE" true true false 8 Date 0 0 ,First,#,BlacksCrosswicks_waterway,FDATE,-1,-1,penn_trib_water,FDATE,-1,-1,raccoon_waterways,FDATE,-1,-1,rancocas_waterways,FDATE,-1,-1;RESOLUTION "RESOLUTION" true true false 10 Long 0 10 ,First,#,BlacksCrosswicks_waterway,RESOLUTION,-1,-1,penn_trib_water,RESOLUTION,-1,-1,raccoon_waterways,RESOLUTION,-1,-1,rancocas_waterways,RESOLUTION,-1,-1;GNIS_ID "GNIS_ID" true true false 10 Text 0 0 ,First,#,BlacksCrosswicks_waterway,GNIS_ID,-1,-1,penn_trib_water,GNIS_ID,-1,-1,raccoon_waterways,GNIS_ID,-1,-1,rancocas_waterways,GNIS_ID,-1,-1;GNIS_NAME "GNIS_NAME" true true false 65 Text 0 0 ,First,#,BlacksCrosswicks_waterway,GNIS_NAME,-1,-1,penn_trib_water,GNIS_NAME,-1,-1,raccoon_waterways,GNIS_NAME,-1,-1,rancocas_waterways,GNIS_NAME,-1,-1;AREASQKM "AREASQKM" true true false 19 Double 0 0 ,First,#,BlacksCrosswicks_waterway,AREASQKM,-1,-1,penn_trib_water,AREASQKM,-1,-1,raccoon_waterways,AREASQKM,-1,-1,rancocas_waterways,AREASQKM,-1,-1;ELEVATION "ELEVATION" true true false 19 Double 0 0 ,First,#,BlacksCrosswicks_waterway,ELEVATION,-1,-1,penn_trib_water,ELEVATION,-1,-1,raccoon_waterways,ELEVATION,-1,-1,rancocas_waterways,ELEVATION,-1,-1;REACHCODE "REACHCODE" true true false 14 Text 0 0 ,First,#,BlacksCrosswicks_waterway,REACHCODE,-1,-1,penn_trib_water,REACHCODE,-1,-1,raccoon_waterways,REACHCODE,-1,-1,rancocas_waterways,REACHCODE,-1,-1;FTYPE "FTYPE" true true false 10 Long 0 10 ,First,#,BlacksCrosswicks_waterway,FTYPE,-1,-1,penn_trib_water,FTYPE,-1,-1,raccoon_waterways,FTYPE,-1,-1,rancocas_waterways,FTYPE,-1,-1;FCODE "FCODE" true true false 10 Long 0 10 ,First,#,BlacksCrosswicks_waterway,FCODE,-1,-1,penn_trib_water,FCODE,-1,-1,raccoon_waterways,FCODE,-1,-1,rancocas_waterways,FCODE,-1,-1;FTYPE_DESC "FTYPE_DESC" true true false 50 Text 0 0 ,First,#,BlacksCrosswicks_waterway,FTYPE_DESC,-1,-1,penn_trib_water,FTYPE_DESC,-1,-1,raccoon_waterways,FTYPE_DESC,-1,-1,rancocas_waterways,FTYPE_DESC,-1,-1;FCODE_DESC "FCODE_DESC" true true false 254 Text 0 0 ,First,#,BlacksCrosswicks_waterway,FCODE_DESC,-1,-1,penn_trib_water,FCODE_DESC,-1,-1,raccoon_waterways,FCODE_DESC,-1,-1,rancocas_waterways,FCODE_DESC,-1,-1;SHAPE_Leng "SHAPE_Leng" true true false 19 Double 0 0 ,First,#,BlacksCrosswicks_waterway,SHAPE_Leng,-1,-1,penn_trib_water,SHAPE_Leng,-1,-1,raccoon_waterways,SHAPE_Leng,-1,-1,rancocas_waterways,SHAPE_Leng,-1,-1;SHAPE_Area "SHAPE_Area" true true false 19 Double 0 0 ,First,#,BlacksCrosswicks_waterway,SHAPE_Area,-1,-1,penn_trib_water,Shape_Area,-1,-1,raccoon_waterways,SHAPE_Area,-1,-1,rancocas_waterways,SHAPE_Area,-1,-1;OBJECTID_1 "OBJECTID_1" true true false 10 Long 0 10 ,First,#,penn_trib_water,OBJECTID_1,-1,-1;Shape_Le_1 "Shape_Le_1" true true false 19 Double 0 0 ,First,#,penn_trib_water,Shape_Le_1,-1,-1"</Process></lineage></DataProperties><SyncDate>20190625</SyncDate><SyncTime>12553500</SyncTime></Esri><dataIdInfo><envirDesc Sync="TRUE"> Version 6.2 (Build 9200) ; Esri ArcGIS 10.5.0.6491</envirDesc><dataLang><languageCode value="eng" Sync="TRUE"></languageCode><countryCode value="USA" Sync="TRUE"></countryCode></dataLang><idCitation><resTitle Sync="TRUE">del_trib_waters</resTitle><presForm><PresFormCd value="005" Sync="TRUE"></PresFormCd></presForm></idCitation><spatRpType><SpatRepTypCd value="001" Sync="TRUE"></SpatRepTypCd></spatRpType></dataIdInfo><mdLang><languageCode value="eng" Sync="TRUE"></languageCode><countryCode value="USA" Sync="TRUE"></countryCode></mdLang><mdChar><CharSetCd value="004" Sync="TRUE"></CharSetCd></mdChar><distInfo><distFormat><formatName Sync="TRUE">Shapefile</formatName></distFormat><distTranOps><transSize Sync="TRUE">0.000</transSize></distTranOps></distInfo><mdHrLv><ScopeCd value="005" Sync="TRUE"></ScopeCd></mdHrLv><mdHrLvName Sync="TRUE">dataset</mdHrLvName><refSysInfo><RefSystem><refSysID><identCode code="3424" Sync="TRUE"></identCode><idCodeSpace Sync="TRUE">EPSG</idCodeSpace><idVersion Sync="TRUE">8.9.3(9.3.0.0)</idVersion></refSysID></RefSystem></refSysInfo><spatRepInfo><VectSpatRep><geometObjs Name="del_trib_waters"><geoObjTyp><GeoObjTypCd value="002" Sync="TRUE"></GeoObjTypCd></geoObjTyp><geoObjCnt Sync="TRUE">0</geoObjCnt></geometObjs><topLvl><TopoLevCd value="001" Sync="TRUE"></TopoLevCd></topLvl></VectSpatRep></spatRepInfo><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20190625</mdDateSt></metadata>
